Sandeep Chauhan

+91-6005030657

Stackoverflow Github LinkedIn

sandeepsajan0@gmail.com Moradabad, India

Summary I'm a Software Developer with 3 years of volunteer experience in Backend development. I have major experience with Python and Django. I love to work remotely with global developers. I have good problem-solving skills. I am a quick learner and passionate about scale applications.

Experience

Eoraa Full-time(Backend Developer)

Apr 2020-Present

- Developed backend APIs for mobile and CMS of a japan based travel company.
- Building an online food order management application backend as a lead developer.
- Developed all time data upload APIs and done with other important tasks.

Remote Inning Part-time Contract(Full-stack developer)

Jan 2020 - March 2020

- Developed the backend APIs with the JWT Authentication for a single-tenant and multi-tenant architecture applications.
- Integrate Wagtail CMS with a static site template, create its models, templates, templatetags and etc.
- Upgrade the cookiecutter-django-foundation with the foundation site's version.

Spoonshot Intern(Full-stack developer)

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Scaling and performance improvements of web crawlers implemented using Python/Django.
- Deployed a proxymanager for scraping framework on Django server with Redis.
- Dockerize the scraping framework and scale it with mongodb, celery workers and aws.
- Implement monitoring systems with Grafana and influxdb.

<u>Hydra Ecosystem</u> Google Summer of Code(Student)

April 2018 - Aug 2018

- Python based implementation of <u>Hydra Client</u>.
- Implemented Hydra Client with the datastore Redis which also works as a cache for Hydrus.
- Developed a web app using flask for hydra-client demo.

Open Source Contribution

• hydra-python-agent One of the main contributors who have built this project.

Implemented Redis as a graph database using redisgraph and Cypher. Also created a Docker env., write tests, use designing patterns etc.

- <u>hydrus</u> Add UUID in database and also add auto documentation using sphinx and fix some easy issues.
- hydra-astrodemo Created a demo for hydra-client using flask which also using the hydra-parser and hydrus server.
- http-apis.github.io Write documention for all the work done by me and also for some other projects related to my work.

Projects

• Wagtail-centrarium

Portfolio site, using a static template(centrarium), with the great Wagtail CMS features. Portfolio sites can be generated in less than 2 mins with the help of this project.

Go Web App

A Web app implemented with Golang using Redis as a database having features routing, authentication, middleware, comments, error handling. It is a good reference for beginners because of its modules and good structure.

Reactjs Projects

- Calculator
- o router-sample
- friends passion(Beginner-friendly project to iterate over json data)
- ReactSwapi_Api(React app to consume api and show data of swapi.co)

Friends

An anonymous web chat app implemented with Python, Django, Reactjs with database sqlite3 have some great functionalities like authentication, public and private groups(without showing users), API's, messaging/posting, API's data presenting using Reactjs.

Social Networking

A blogpost web app which is implemented using Python, Django and PostgreSQL as a database having features like authentication, manage profiling, blogs posting (with date and name). It is live or deployed on heroku.

Education

Bachelor of Technology(2016-2020(expected))

On it Made Visite to Best Made and Italian and Itali

Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, katra, India

Miscellaneous

• Student mentor/guide at The CodeClub, SMVDU.

Skills

Backend Development: Python(Django, Wagtail), Golang **Frontend Development:** React.js, HTML and CSS, JS **Databases:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Mongodb, sqlite

Operating System: Linux(ubuntu)

Other tools: Git, Bash, Docker, Celery, RabbitMQ, Grafana, influxdb, AWS